Guide to the Records of John Brademas Speeches 1965-1991 RG 3.0.10 RG 3.0.10
New York University Archives
John Brademas NYU Presidential Speeches
1980-1991
RG 3.0.10
New York University Archives
17.0 Linear feet 17 linear feet (17 boxes)
This collection contains the addresses given by John Brademas, President Emeritus of New York University. The balance of Brademas' NYU presidential papers will be made available when the 20 year restricted period has elapsed.
Brademas, John, 1927-
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically.
The files are grouped into one series.
Series I
Scope and Content Note
The Speeches of John Brademas contain the public addresses given by Brademas, President Emeritus of New York University from 1981 to 1991. The speeches are arranged in chronological order from 1965 to 1991.
Historical/Biographical Note
John Brademas, President Emeritus of New York University, served as president from 1981 to 1992. During that time, he led the transition of NYU from a regional commuter school to a national and international residential research university. Before coming to New York, he served as U.S. Representative in Congress from Indiana for 22 years (1959-81), the last four as House Majority Whip. In Congress he earned a reputation for his leadership in education and the arts. Former Chairman of the President's Committee on the Arts and the Humanities, the National Endowment for Democracy and the Board of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, he is president of the King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center of New York University Foundation. He is a Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and member of the National Academy of Education (USA), The Academy of Athens, European Academy of Science and Arts and National Academy of Education of Argentina. In 2004 he was elected to the New York State Board of Regents by the New York State Legislature.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Provenance
Brademas, John, 1927-; New York University. Office of the President.; New York University.; Speeches.
- Series I
  - Removed to John Brademas Congressional collection (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    bar code: 3 1142 042254584
  - ART Brademas Article in "Art News" (By Mary Lynn Kotz), Sep 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brademas - Breakfast Congress, Wash., DC (Various Back-Up), Apr 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hon. Ray Thorton, Pres. Arkansas State Univ., Jonesboro, AR, Apr 16, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Brademas Springfield College Address, Springfield MA, International Education, May 24, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - NYU Law School Convocation, May 28, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brademas Bennett Interview for NYU Report, Jun 5, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Testimonial Dinner for Dr. Brademas Corcoran Gallery (Mr. Tisch's Remarks), Wash., DC, Jun 8, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Presidential Inauguration Memo (Invitations & Program), Jun 16, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Brademas Memo to Deans & Vice Pres. (Appt. of Dr. Wolanin), Jun 17, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Welcome Message for Summer Orientation of New Torch, Jun 1, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Role of the Federal Government in Support of Museums, Milan, Italy, Jun 24, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - GPA Arts Institute, NYU, Jul 17, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Foreign Lawyers Workshop Dinner, NYU (International Education), Jul 23, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Anglo-American Conf. on Univ. Admin., Rockefeller Plaza, Jul 28, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Career in Business Reception, NYU, Jul 9, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - ARA Services Quarterly Management ,Committee Meeting, NYU, Aug 12, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Greek American Involvement in Contempory American Politics, Chios, Greece, Aug 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Role of Congress in American Foreign Policy, Chios, Greece, Aug 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Chios Arts & Museums Speech, Chios, Greece, Aug 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - International Education, Chios, Greece, Aug 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "American Higher Education & The Federal Role", Chios, Greece, Aug 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Writers at Work Program, NYU, Sep 18, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Freshmen Orientation Remarks, NYU, Sep 21, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Presidential Citation Presentation to Czeslaw Milosz, NYU ( Mr. Milosz' Career NYU & the Arts), Sep 22, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - The Cotzias Award Dinner American Parkinson Disease Assn. Honoring George P. Livanos, Sep 23, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Waldorf Astoria (Greece Medicine Federal Funds for Medicine), undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Architecture of NYU (Dr.Brademas), Sep 23, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Herber Silverman Remarks "Architecture of NYU" (Exhibit), Sep 23, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Dr. Brademas Remarks Cardinal Konig, Sep 28, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cardinal Konig Luncheon (Religion & Science (Proposal for "Nova Spes Project" is in Folder - Science & Humanity), Sep 28, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Delmore Schwartz Prize to Constance Urdang, Sep 30, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Crick Lecture & Seminar, Oct 1, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Dr. Brademas Inaugural Remarks, Oct 9, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Trustee Presentation, Oct 12, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - The Inaugural Medal of Freedom Award Dinner, Oct 13, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - City Hall Ceremonies NYU Week Proclamation, Oct 13, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Herbert Silverman Remarks for Proclamation of NYU Week at City Hall, Oct 13, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Laurence Tisch Remarks for Proclamation of NYU Week at City Hall, Oct 13, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Dr. Brademas Inauguaral Program, Avery Fischer Hall, (Address on his Inaguration), Oct 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Laurence Tisch Remarks for Inaugural Ceremonies, Oct 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Laurence Tisch Remarks for Toast at Inagural Brunch, Oct 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Herbert Silverman Remarks for Inaugural Ceremonies, Oct 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Dr. Brademas Remarks for Inaugural Brunch, Avery Fisher Hall, Oct 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Michael Widman's Inaugural Remarks (Student Council), Oct 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Dr. Brademas Remarks at Dinner, Oct 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Sequicentennial Calendar Foreword by Dr. Brademas, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Trustee Report, Fall 1981 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Dr. Oliva Remarks for Inaugural Ceremonies, Oct 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Dr. Brademas Inaugural Program, Oct 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Press Kit for Dr. Brademas Inauguration (Various Materials), Oct 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - FAS "Dimensions of Change" Conference, NYU (NYU & the Arts), Oct 15, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Dr. Brademas Remarks for Town Hall Friend of the Arts Award, NYU Univ. Club, (Art/Museums Fed. Support for the Arts, Art in General), Oct 18, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Annual Report Drafts (NYU in General), Oct 19, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Gallatin Dinner, NYU, (Dr. Brademas Goals for NYU), Oct 26, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Coles Dedication Center, NYU, (Resources of Coles Center Dr. and Mrs. Coles), Oct 24, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Laurance Tisch Remarks at the Coles Dedication, NYU, (Sports), Oct 24, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Varsity Club Dinner (Award to Dr. Coles), NYU, (Sports, Cole's Sports Center), Oct 27, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Breakfast for Dr. Hans-Jochen Vogel (German Politician & Author), NYU, (Deutsches Haus Vogel's Career), Oct 28, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Degree Presentation to Professor Friedrichs (Mathematician), NYU, (Courant), Oct 30, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - State of the Univ. Address to the Trustees (Presentation), NYU, (Overview of NYU Schools), Nov 2, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Public Educ. Assoc. Luncheon, Waldorf Astoria NY, (Federal Funds for Educ., Public Educ.), Nov 4, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - IFA (Goals for NYU International Studies), Nov 4, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - New York Library Assoc. Conference, Statler Hilton, NY, (Libraries in General Gov. Funds), Nov 7, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Miller Conference, Urbana, IL, ("The Academy and the Main Human Enterprise", Higher Educ., Gov. Budget Cuts), Nov 9, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Liberal Arts Education & Study in Spain, NYU, (International Studies), Nov 13, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Annual Report Statement (NYU in General), undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Vanderbilt Associates Dinner, NYU, (Arts, International Educ., NYU in General, Liberal Arts), Nov 18, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Hellenic Chamber of Commerce (U.S. and Greece/ International Education), Nov 19, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Assn. for a Better New York Breakfast, Waldorf Astoria NY, (Goals for NYU, NYU & New York City, Educ. & Private Sector), Nov 20, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Carnegie Foundation Colloquium at Georgetown Univ., Wash., DC ("Higher Learning & The Nations Future"), Nov 24, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Div. of Student Affairs & Services, NYU, (NYU Fundraising Goals), Nov 24, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Corporate Dinner (Development), NY, (NYU & Corporate), Nov 24, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - American Physical Society, NYU, (NYU & Science), Dec 3, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Henry Draper Symposium, NYU, (Draper- Astrophysicist), Dec 4, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - GPA Report to the Faculty (Dr. Brademas Remarks) --Files Missing, NYU, Dec 8, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - "Dr. Brademas' Letter to the Trustees, NYU, ( Wash. Square,. Off-Campus Activities, Reports to the Faculty,Leadership Campaign Major Gifts, Academic News & Notes ", Dec 8, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Council on Foreign Affairs Dinner, Wash., DC (Congress & Foreign Policy), Dec 9, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Higher Education Group, Wash. DC, (Problems Re: Higher Education), Dec 9, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - University Senate, NYU, (Presentation- NYU in General, Medical Center, Dr. Brademas Plans for NYU Leadership), Dec 10, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Research Libraries Group, NYU, (Liberal Arts, Record of Gov. Aid to Educ., Reagan Budget Cuts Support from Private Sector), Dec 10, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 042254592
  - Taft Accolades for Walter Mondale (Former Colleagues in Washington), Dec 10, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - SCE, NYU, (Importance of SCE, Re: Adult Education), Dec 11, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty of Arts and Science, NYU, (Importance of Arts and Science), Dec 14, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Academic Libraries Frontier, UCLA, (Liberal Arts, Record of Gov. Aid to Educ., Reagan Budget Cuts, Support from Private Sector, Dec 16, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - SOA Faculty (Dr. Brademas Remarks) Remarks Not in File, Jan 5, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fulbright Commission in Israel, Jerusalem, Israel (Int'l Education, Benefits of Fulbright Exchange, Only Memo), Jan 12, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Night Talk" - Taping (Dr. Brademas Remarks), NYU, (NYU Programs in Television), Jan 28, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Village Chamber of Commerce Lunch, NYU, (History of NYU & Village), Feb 3, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Institute of Fine Arts (Dr. Brademas Remarks), IFA, (Trip to Israel, Egypt & Paris), Feb 3, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - School of Social Work (Dr. Brademas Remarks), NYU, (NYU in General Fundraising), Feb 8, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - George Heyman Remarks to Exec. Comm. of Trustees,NYU, (Announcement of Larry & Robert Tisch's Gift), Feb 8, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dr. Brademas Report to Exec. Committee of Trustees, NYU, (Same As Feb. 11 Report to Faculty), Feb 8, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Dr. Brademas Remarks to the Faculty of Business Admin., NYU, (Resources of NYU and NYC), Feb 9, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dr. Brademas' Remarks to the Univ. Senate, NYU, (Larry & Robert Tisch's Gift, Appt. of Gilligan, Trip to Israel, Egypt & Paris, University's Budget, Dental School, Reagan's Budget Cuts), Feb 11, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dr. Brademas Remarks at Brittany Residence Hall (Ribbon Cutting), NYU, (Brief Remarks, Education/Campus, Reagan's Budget Cuts), Feb 12, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Palm Beach Dinner, Palm Beach, (Remarks by Ruth Farkas, Larry Tisch, Herbert Silverman, Dr. Brademas' Speech, Trip to Israel, International Educ., Reagan's Budget Cuts), Feb 18, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Brademas Remarks at Deloitte Haskins & Sells Reception, NYU Cluv, (Background of School and Commerce, Corporate Gifts), Feb 18, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Report to Dental Faculty (Dr. Brademas' Commitments to NYU/Academic, Excellence & Fiscal, Stability, NYU in General, Proposal/NYU & Columbia, Univ. School of Dental & Oral Surgery), Mar 1, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - UN Foreign Language Week, UN, (International Educ.-What it is, Why It Matters, How it Can Be Strengthened in Schools), Mar 1, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Rockfeller Center Luncheon Club,New York, (How Budget Cuts Will Effect Educ.-Private, Sector/Voluntarism), Mar 2, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Reception & Presentation of Gift from the Education & Vocation for the Deaf Foundation, NYU, (NYU & the Hearing Impaired), Mar 2, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Hearing of the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, NYU, (Effects of Reagan's Budget Cuts), Feb 5, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Welcoming Subcomittee/Post Secondary Educ. Hearings, NYU, (Reagan's Budget Cuts/Arts), Mar 5, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Alpha Omega Council, Boston, (Dr. Brademas "Man of Year", Greek/Americans & Politics, Reagan's Budget Cuts), Mar 6, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Social Work Education, NYU, (Dr. Brademas' Commitment to Social Justice, Effects of Reagan's Budget Cuts), Mar 7, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Mason & Sons Dedication Breakfast,NYU, (International Educ.), Mar 7, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Chet Huntiey Memorial Lecture, NYU, (Welcome Remarks NYU & Media), Mar 10, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - University Senate, NYU, (Outreach in Palm Beach, Reagan's Budget Cuts, Admissions, housing etc.), Mar 11, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Luncheon Meeting of NYU Financial Finance Club, Two World Trade Center, Past Record of Gov. Aid to Educ., Budget Cuts, Graduate Educ, Voluntarism, NYU in General), Mar 11, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Public Education/SEHNAP- Does Public Education Have a Future?, NYU, (Various Legislation for Education that Dr. Brademas Was Involved with Reagan's Federalism), Mar 13, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Public Interest Lecture of the Cosmopolitan Club, Cosmopolitan Club, NYU & The Arts, Brademas & the Arts- As Congressman, Reagan's Budget Cuts, Voluntarism), Mar 15, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Report to Board of Trustees, NYU, (Financial Aid, Dental Center, Admissions, Registration, Hayden Hall/Housing), Mar 15, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Real Estate Institute Annual Urban Leadership Award, NYU, (History of Future of Real Estate Institute), Mar 18, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Faculty Council (Talking Points), NYU, (Budet, College of Dentistry, Medical Center, Financial Aid), Mar 18, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Congressional Breakfast (Talking Points), NYU, (Welcome Remarks), Mar 21, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - American Education Research Assoc., New York, Hilton ( National Inst. of Educ.,Thinkers & Doers, Reagan Budget Cuts, Shift in Gov. Attitudes, Prospects for Research, Old Commitments & New Realities Ignored, Signs of Muddled Thinking, The Polity of Education, Welcome Remarks), Mar 22, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Dental College Sesqui. Dinner, (Reagan Budget Cuts Albany), Mar 22, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Medical School Faculty Mtg., (Effects of Reagan's Budget Cuts), Mar 23, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Herbert Silverman Remarks at Dental Center 150th Celebration, Plaza Hotel, (Background of Dental Center), Mar 23, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - (On Tape) Dental Center Ambassador Program Inauguration, (Fundraising), Mar 24, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Friends of Greek Studies, Ball State Univ., (Foreign Language, International Studies, America's Future), Mar 24, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - 9th S. J. Brademas Sr. Lecture Ball State Univ., Muncie, IN, (Dr. Giles Constable), Mar 25, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Moskowitz Lecture/Brademas, NYU, (BPA, Reagan Budget Cuts), Mar 31, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Publishers Lunch Club, Yale Club, (Reagan Admin., Restriction of Access to Gov. Info), Apr 1, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Administrator's Roundtable, CUNY, NY, (Reagan Admin./Effect Budget Cuts will have on Education), Apr 2, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Law School Faculty Meeting, NYU, (Housing, Law School, Development), Apr 5, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Reception/Journal of International Law & Politics, (Brief Remarks), Apr 6, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Dr. Brademas Remarks at Lord Caradon Dinner, NYU, (Lord Caradon's Career, International Educ.), Apr 12, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Dr. Brademas Remarks at Lord Briggs Lecture, NYU, (Lord Briggs Career, Continuing Educ.), Apr 14, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Senate Meeting (Dr. Brademas Remarks), NYU, (Development- Housing, Etc), Apr 15, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Administrator's Roundtable of the City College of New York, City College of NY, Apr 20, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Postgrad & Univ. Hosp. Alumni Assoc. Dinner. (Reagan Admin. & Effects of Budget Cuts in Medicine & Research), Apr 20, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Leo Jaffe Dinner, NYU, (Jaffe's Career), Apr 21, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - David Kriser Seminar Topic: Nuclear Arms, NYU, (Welcome Remarks/ David Kriser & Dr. Brademas), Apr 22, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Theodore M. Hesburg Citation (Founders Day), NYU, Apr 22, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Founders Day Dinner & Convocation, NYU, (Scholarship), Apr 22, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - 160th Commencement Exercises- Univ. Of Pittsburg, Pittsburg, (Comparision Between Being a Congressman & Pres. Of NYU), Apr 25, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - School of Social Work Benefit, NYU Club, (Affects of Reagan Admin. Budget Cuts), Apr 25, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Sunrise Semester Talking Points, ("Affect of Public Policy on Human Development", Educ, Health, Etc., Dr. Brademas' Involvement with Handicapped Children Act), Apr 26, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Association for a Better NY & American Jewish Community, (Bus. & Educ. Technology,Legislation Dr. Brademas Helped Pass & Now Trying to Preserve), Apr 28, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Installation of Howard Squadron as President of the American Jewish Congress, Gorssinger's NY, (Comments, I/E/ inner with Ambassador Ghorbal of Egypt), Apr 28, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 042254600
  - Gallatin Div./10th Anniv., (NYU), Experimental Educ., College Turmoil in 1960s, Reagan Admin./Freedom of Info. Act), Apr 30, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Italina Heritage & Culture Week Proclamation Ceremony (Brademas & Oliva), Wash. Sq. Park, (Brademas: Immigrants and NYU Village, Olivia: Italian Explorers), Apr 30, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Toast for Dinner/Auchincloss, (Greeting to Auchincloss & Guests), May 19, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conf. - Central America & The Caribbean, NYU, (International Educ. & NYU Welcome Remarks Etc. (2 pages)), May 2, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Caring Community Lunch, NYU, (Village, Brademas' Efforts to Help the Elderly As Congressman), May 6, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Meeting with Student Senators Council Talking Points, NYU, (Financial Aid Etc.), May 6, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - University Senate, NYU, (Wash/Albany, Carey, Etc.), May 6, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees, NYU, (Contributions to NYU, Brademas' Efforts Re: Fundraising), May 10, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Indiana Univeristy Commencement Talking Points, South Bend, IN, (Comparison Between Congressman and NYU Press, Etc), May 11, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1982 Commencement Exercises Univ. of Southern California, Southern CA, (Reagan Admin/Budget BPA, Cuts and Voluntarism), May 13, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Meeting with the Marketing Society Talking Points, NYU/NPA. (Excellence of BPA, BPA Clubs, NYU & Clubs, May 18, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Japan International Christian Univeristy Foundation Luncheon, NYU, (Lewis Levine Language Lab. Admissions, Dev. Report, Albany/Wash Update), May 20, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Faculty Council Talking Points, NYU, (Lewis Levine Language Lab., Admissions, Dev. Report, Albany/Wash Update), May 20, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Washington Square Assoc. Talking Points (Comparison- Indiana & Wash., DC, Life in Village, History of Wash. Square), May 20, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Graduation Ceremonies Manchester College, North Manchester, IN, (Social Concern, Relationship of the Christian Faith to the Public Order), May 23, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Andrew Huxley/Convocation & Dinner, NYU Med. Ctr., (Huxley's Background), May 24, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Brademas Remarks/Weiler Award to Gov. Cary, Pierre Hotel, NY (Carey's Career & Accomplishments in Government, May 25, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Alumni Federation Dinner, NYU, (Contributions to NYU Remarks for Award Presentations), May 27, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - NYU Med. School Commencement, Lincoln Center, (Mayor Koch), Jun 2, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - NYU Commencement Address to the 34th Annual Business Conference, Rutgers Univ, (Economy-World Human Capital Problems & Solutions, Re: Technology Service Industries), Jun 3, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Executive Committee/Board of Trustees, NYU, (Reagan Admin., CA Trip, International Educ., Etc.), Jun 7, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Administrative Management Council, NYU, (Financial Aid, Brademas Trip to CA, Brademas Goals for NYU, International Education- School of Arts, Housing, Increasing Fundraising), Jun 9, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Trustees Pre-Commencement Dinner,NYU, (Remarks for Recipients of Hon. Degrees (See 06/10/82 for Names)), Jun 9, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - NYU Commencement Silverman Remarks, Jun 10, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - NYU Commencement Tisch Remarks, Jun 10, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - NYU Commencement Brademas Remarks (Defense Budget), Jun 10, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - NYU Commencement Script, NYU, (Citations to: James Tobin, Sir Isaiah Berlin, Sarah Caldwell, Stephen W. Hawking, Henry Kaufman, Bayard Rustin), Jun 10, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Commencement Exercises at Kalamazoo College, Kalamazoo, MI, (International Education), Jun 12, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - DePaul University Commencement Exercises, Chicago, IL, (Reagan Admin./ Budget Cuts), Jun 13, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Citizens Budget Commission Press, NYU, (International Education), Jun 14, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Nat'1 Assoc. of College & Univ. Attorneys, Waldorf Astoria,NY, (Attributes a Lawyer Needs), Jul 8, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Luncheon Meeting International House of Japan, Tokyo, Japan, ( America's Trade Balance with Japan, American Opinions of Japan, Japanese Alumni), undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Seminar on U.S. - Japan Economic Relations, Aspen, CO, ( America's Trade Balance with Japan, American Opinions of Japan), Aug 16, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Education Commission of the States in Portland (James Bryant Conant Award), Portland, OR, (Brademas Background), Aug 20, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Academic Convocation for New Students, (General Advice to Students, Attractions of NY), Sep 9, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Education Panel of Biennial Conf. Of the Nat'l Intal, & American Foundation, Wash. Hilton, Wash. DC, (NYU & Ital. Amer. Community, Courses and Programs at NYU, Faculty, Students, Richard Gambin's "Blood of my Blood", Sep 10, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Opening Convocation Univ. of Richmond, Richmond, VA, (Reagan Admin. & Aid to Educ.) Biennial Conference of the National American Foundation- --Files Missing, Portland, OR, Sep 15, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 38)